# Nethra Mugala

nethra.af68@gmail.com | (937) 516 2193 | Miami, FL 33126

https://www.linkedin.com/in/nethra-65b58485/ | https://nethraui.github.io/myportfolio.github.io/

## **SUMMARY**

Experienced in object-oriented programming, developing, testing, debugging code and designing interfaces. Developed web applications from scratch using Dojo framework and RESTful APIs. Capable of learning quick and master new technologies. Strong troubleshooting and problem-solving skills with an analytical mindset.

## **EDUCATION**

Wright State University - Fairborn, OH

2016 - 2018

Master's: Computer Engineering

G. Narayanamma Institute of Technology and Science, INDIA

2012 - 2016

Bachelor's: Electronics and Communication Engineering

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Dojo, React, RESTful Web services.

Languages: Java, C, C++, Python

Databases: Oracle, IBM DB2, SQL Server, Firebase Database, Firebase Storage

Applications/Tools: IBM Rational Application Developer (RAD), Visual Studio Code, Eclipse, IntelliJ, WebSphere, IBM Http server,

Tomcat, Postman, SQL Developer, JIRA, Jenkins, UCD

Version Controls: Bitbucket, SourceTree, Git

## **WORK HISTORY**

## Software Developer | NextEra Energy - Miami, FL

May 2019 - Current

- Improved user experience measured by an increase in customer satisfaction by 25% by developing web application using Dojo framework.
- Built *RESTful APIs using Java* to export the data to external application.
- Implemented webpage migration from Struts to Dojo framework to make it work on multiple devices and *optimize query time* reducing it by 50%.
- Released 3 new features into production within span of 2 months. Managed milestones from initial steps through final delivery.
- Developed reusable components to use across projects which reduced rework for developers by 15%.
- Consulted with Product Manager to identify minimal viable product and decomposed feature set into small scoped user stories.

#### Software Developer Intern | Tres Mercari Group, India

March 2016 – July 2016

- Developed company's page using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and JavaScript and used jQuery, AJAX via JSON to request data and update the HTML page.
- Oversaw all the stages of Software Development Life Cycle including quality assurance and integration testing.
- Learned software engineering process improvements and best practices.

#### **PROJECTS**

## **Bus Booking application**

Lead a team of 4 and developed a bus booking system that allows users to register, login and search for the bus based of date, time and allows admin to login to their account and add new buses and delete if any bus was canceled.

Technologies used: Spring Boot, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, IntelliJ, PostgreSQL, Tomcat Server, Postman, JavaMailSender

## Android Application

Course Project for Distributed Computing

Lead a team of 5 and developed an android application, which is designed to connect a tourist and a guide at a tourist place and then charge for the tour duration at the end of the session. I built Login and Register pages and stored credentials in Firebase Database. *Technologies used:* HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Android Studio, Firebase, Google Maps API

#### Weather Application

Designed a prototype for weather application in Adobe XD for every screen size and then Developed a Responsive Weather application using ReactJS in Visual Studio Code, which takes place as input and gives Temperature, Humidity and Weather condition. Used Weather API to get weather information and used fetch () method to get the data from the API. For UI design, Flexbox layout is used, and Bootstrap dependency is installed through npm.

Technologies used: Adobe XD, HTML5, CSS3, ReactJS, Bootstrap, npm, Weather API, Google Fonts, Visual Studio Code